BRENDAN JANG



OBJECTIVE

To advance my career with a leading organization that will utilize my extensive software and programming knowledge while also allowing me to develop further as a professional

Proven talent for aligning business strategy and objectives with established software and development paradigms to achieve maximum operational impacts with minimum resource expenditures. Growth-focused thought leader known for expertise with Python and proficiency with C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL and Selenium. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills, as well as team leadership, process optimization, and resource allocation expertise.

PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS

- Haunted Mansion: Text based escape room game built using Python.
- PWGen: Generates and stores random passwords in a designated txt file.
- CodingResources: Personal website project for resources on learning how to code.
- Wasteagram: Mobile app inspired by Instagram to track daily waste in the food industry.
- *Splittrip*: Web app to keep track of supplies and purchases made by a group.
- JobScraper: Python script to scrape job boards for new jobs matching specific criteria.

More project examples

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Data management
- Data analysis
- Strategy development

- Process optimization
- Relationship management
- Team leadership

- Problem solving
- Communication
- Collaboration

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SERRANO EYE CENTER MEDICAL GROUP, LOS ANGELES, CALIFORNIA, MARCH 2016 TO PRESENT

MANAGER IN TRAINING, OCTOBER 2019 TO PRESENT

- Developed and implemented a new system for tracking and handling office income using Excel, which streamlined processes and increased office efficiency.
- Oversee the hiring and training of new and current employees in multiple departments, including IT, surgery, marketing, and billing, ensuring new hires were informed of best practices and policies.
- Led the process automation and revamping of calculating employee hours for payroll using Python file input/output, which reduced time spent on payroll and increased accuracy.
- Ensure office computers stayed up to date and healthy through routine software, hardware, and network checks, as well as proactively strategizing to prevent malfunctions.
- Provide guidance to current employees, helping build high-performing teams and driving department productivity.
- Demonstrated ability to optimize operations and lead teams in high-stress situations.

BILLING MANAGER, JULY 2018 TO PRESENT

- Managed a team of three, quickly and efficiently handling the medical billing process for Medicare, Medical, HMO, and Commercial claims.
- Assessed and identified unpaid and denied insurance claims using practice management reports and handled claim reprocessing and denial management effectively.
- Prepared and ran monthly reports aiming to identify and correct problem areas in the billing process, and developed strategies for improvement areas based on the reports.
- Spearheaded the implementation of new billing procedures that contributed to a 20.9% increase in net payments collected from insurance companies in 2019.

Brendan Jang Page 2

• Built a custom script that compared current and previous years' office income and flagged negative performance.

SURGERY COORDINATOR, MARCH 2016 TO JULY 2018

- Liaised and coordinated with surgeons and ambulatory surgery centers to schedule patients for surgery, prioritizing high-risk cases and managing various patients simultaneously.
- Drove and increase in premium lens unit sales by 74%, resulting in 56% growth in net income from lenses during 2016 to 2018.
- Generated scripts for outpatient tests and procedures as ordered per physician.
- Responsible to continually monitor the schedule looking for inefficiencies, as well as strategizing for improvement.
- Informs office staff and distributes the schedule to the office and the other two facilities for surgery.

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

MASTER OF SCIENCE (M.Sc.) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, IN PROGRESS
Georgia Tech University, Atlanta Georgia

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.Sc.) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, 2021
Oregon State University, Corvallis, Oregon

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: English, Korean

Technical Proficiencies: Python, C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Selenium, Flask, Flutter/Dart

Interests: Fishing, Basketball (recreational),